{
    "id": "d3ea8c9f54324dc1935e578e59b05a9e",
    "title": "Comparatives and Superlatives | Grammar Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "1e76aade8bea49e7b7010bbd9068e025",
            "title": "Comparatives and Superlatives | Grammar Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "It is more expensive ......................... I thought.",
                    "description": "Then is an adverb of time. In comparative expressions we use than.",
                    "answers": [
                        "as",
                        "than",
                        "then"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Chennai is ................................. Mumbai.",
                    "description": "We do not normally use 'the' before a comparative adjective + than.",
                    "answers": [
                        "the hotter than",
                        "hotter than",
                        "hotter then"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Susie is .............................. of the two sisters.",
                    "description": "When a group consists of just two people or things, we prefer the comparative to the superlative. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "prettier",
                        "the prettier",
                        "the prettiest"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Mary is ................................ student in the class.",
                    "description": "Before superlative adjectives, we use 'the'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "best",
                        "the best",
                        "the better",
                        "better"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He is not .............................. his brother.",
                    "description": "To say that people or things are not equal in a particular way we use the structure not as + adjective + as.",
                    "answers": [
                        "as successful than",
                        "successful than",
                        "as successful as",
                        "more successful as"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "The car is running ............................ since it had a service.",
                    "description": "Both smoothly and more smoothly are possible here. However, 'more smoothly' is the preferred form. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "smoothly",
                        "more smoothly",
                        "most smoothly",
                        "Either smoothly or more smoothly"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "It was ............................ dress I have ever worn.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "most expensive",
                        "more expensive",
                        "the most expensive",
                        "the more expensive"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "It was ten times ............................... I expected.",
                    "description": "The expression 'three/four times + comparative' means the same as 'three/four times as much'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "more difficult than",
                        "difficult than",
                        "most difficult than",
                        "more difficult"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I can walk ................................. you.",
                    "description": "The expression 'three/four times + comparative' means the same as 'three/four times as much'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "three times further than",
                        "three times as much as",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "He is ................................ his brother.",
                    "description": "The structure 'three/four times + comparative' is not possible with words like 'twice' and 'half'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "twice as lively as",
                        "twice livelier",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "He explained it carefully, but I was still ..........................",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "all the wiser",
                        "none the wiser",
                        "not the wiser"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The more information that comes in, .....................................",
                    "description": "In structures like these, the word order in both clauses is: the + comparative expression + subject + verb.",
                    "answers": [
                        "the more confused is the picture",
                        "the more confused the picture is",
                        "the more is confused the picture",
                        "the more confused picture is"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}